WILLIAM SEASE

Bluffton, SC 29910 ♦ (843) 290-1823 ♦ mrwsease@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Citrix/VMware/Azure application and desktop delivery
- Powershell and Bash scripting
- Windows, Citrix, Azure, and third party support
- Object oriented programming (C++, C#, Java, Pvthon)
- Full stack development (HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL)
- Docker, Kubernetes, and Terraform
- Linux

- Git
- AWS cloud architecture
- Change control and documentation
- Networking, security, and authentication
- Splunk and ServiceNow
- End user support
- Technical troubleshooting
- Vendor relations
- Data analytics

Professional Summary

Resourceful system administrator and programmer who consistently responds to a wide range of technical challenges with a focused and creative approach. Highly effective at troubleshooting and decision making. Two years of progressive, enterprise-level IT experience and five years of engaging in complex problem-solving through programming.

WORK HISTORY

Client Systems Administrator, 09/2019 - 09/2021

Epic Hosting LLC – Verona, WI

- Maintained multiple customers' Citrix and Azure environments with zero minutes of unplanned Production downtime.
- Merged the Software-as-a-service and third-party integrations between two of the largest hospital networks in the southeastern United States.
- Completed a full transfer of a customer's existing EMR system to Epic Hosting.
- Developed internal scripts to monitor and alert on unexpected shifts in the customers' environments.

Undergraduate Researcher, 01/2018 - 05/2019

Clemson University - Clemson, SC

- Harnessed Clemson's Palmetto supercomputing cluster for retrotransposon research using various programs such as BLAST and LTRHarvest.
- Utilized a wide knowledge of Linux and Python in the search of unique retrotransposons in the Olive Baboon genome.
- Designed a unique workflow for the purpose of comparing two genome's retrotransposons.

Undergraduate Researcher, 09/2017 - 08/2018

Clemson University – Clemson, SC

- Provided technical and constructive services for various projects including: the construction of one (which utilized Raspberry Pi) and mobilization of two CNC machines.
- Supported the genetic aspect of searching for long interspersed elements in the human genome which required specific knowledge of genome browsers and the application of the BLAST program.
- Developed high level skills in collaboration and communication while interacting with and assisting graduate researchers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Biochemistry, 06/2019

Clemson University - Clemson, SC

- Minored in Computer Science
- Received Palmetto Life Scholarship
- Dean's List

CERTIFICATIONS

- Epic Client Systems Administrator, Epic Hosting LLC
- Hosting Azure Presentation Tier Administration, Epic Hosting LLC
- Hosting Hyperspace and Desktop Azure and Horizon Apps, Epic Hosting LLC
- Citrix Certified Associate Virtualization, Citrix
- Google IT Support Specialization, Coursera
- AWS Cloud Solutions Architect, Coursera
- Various Coursera certifications in the field of computer science and IT